issf-sports.org 2019-09-03

# ISSF Privacy Policy

                                                      -1-                                 ISSF Privacy Policy
ISSF Privacy Policy
The International Shooting Sport Federation e.V., Widenmayerstr. 16, 80538 Munich, Germany
(“ISSF”) is the service provider and responsible authority of the ISSF Website. The ISSF is commit-
ted to protect your privacy and personal data and ensure your security when using its website and
services. ISSF strives to be transparent about how we collect and use your information and to keep
your information secure. Throughout this Privacy Policy “Personal Data” means any information
relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, e.g. name, address, IP address etc. Please note
that ISSF Website services are not direct to children below the age of sixteen. ISSF does not know-
ingly collect, use, or share information that could reasonably be used to identify children under age
of sixteen without prior parental consent or consistent with applicable law. Any registration by a
minor would require the parents’ prior consent.
In the following, ISSF informs you on the processing of Personal Data when you are using the ISSF
Website or any service offered on the ISSF Website.
1.         Processing of Personal Data
a)         Visiting the ISSF Website
ISSF temporarily processes the following information when you are visiting the ISSF Website: IP
address, date and time of the request, time zone difference to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT), content
of the request (concrete webpage), access status/http-status code, respective size of transferred data,
website the request has come from, the operating system and its interface, language and version of
the used browser software, videos viewed/audio tracks listened to, individual links clicked, search
words or search phrases (site search), duration of visit.
Such information is anomyzed and used to ensure a smooth connection setup of the website, analyse
trends, administer the website, track users' movements and gather broad demographic information
for aggregate use, which allows ISSF to improve the ISSF Website to its visitors needs, to ensure the
ISSF Website functions correctly and to identify any technical issues as well as for statistical purpos-
es. In addition, the IP address is processed for security reasons, e.g. to identify cyber attacks against
the ISSF Website.
Article 6 para. 1 lit. f of the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) serves as the legal basis for
such processin. Our legitimate interest follows from the purposes of data use listed above. Such in-
formation is neither used to create individual user profiles (“Profiling”) nor forwarded to third par-
ties unless required by state authorities on basis of legal provisions. Please do not visit the ISSF
Website if you do not want to be subject to such anomyzed use of data.
b)         Use of Cookies
Cookies are small text files which are sent to your computer by a web server and saved on your hard
drive so that the web server can “remember” you. The use of Cookies serves our legitimate interests
according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR as explained below. Furthermore, by clicking „OK“ at the first
visit of the ISSF Website you gave consent to the use of cookies. Therefore, also Article 6 para. 1 lit.a
GDPR serves as the legal basis for the use of cookies. You have the possibility to deactivate the use of
Cookies as described below with regard to the respective type of Cookies.
aa)        ISSF Website’s Cookies
The ISSF Website uses Cookies and active components (e.g. JavaScript) to remember
Date: July 2019

                                                      -2-                                 ISSF Privacy Policy
- preferences and to customise the design of the websites,
- already seen infographics pop-ups, so it will not be displayed again for a time,
- your online shopping bag during your shopping activity at the ISSF online shop.
The cookie-related information is not used to identify you personally and the pattern data is fully
under ISSF’s control. These Cookies are not used for any purpose other than those described here.
You may, at any time, prevent the setting of Cookies through the ISSF Website by means of a corre-
sponding setting of your internet browser, and may thus permanently deny the setting of Cookies.
Furthermore, already set Cookies may be deleted at any time via your internet browser which is pos-
sible in all common internet browsers. The deactivating of the ISSF Website’s Cookies could, howev-
er, affect the proper functioning of the ISSF Website in your internet browser.
bb)        Google Analytics
The ISSF Website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc., 1600 Am-
phitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, United States (“Google”). IP anonymization is
activated which means that Google will anonymize the last octet of the IP address for Member States
of the European Union as well as for other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Ar-
ea. Google Analytics uses Cookies to help the website analyse how users use the site. On behalf of the
website provider Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the web-
site, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating
to website activity and internet usage to the website provider. The information generated by the
cookie about your use of the ISSF Website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and
stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will not associate your IP address with any
other data held by Google. Google Analytics is switched off once you log-in to ISSF Website services
which require your registration.
You can prevent Google’s collection and use of data by downloading and installing the browser plug-
in available under this link [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB)].
Further information concerning the terms and conditions of use and data privacy can be found at
www.google.com/analytics/terms/de.html.
c)         ISSF online shop
If you want to place an order at the ISSF online shop on the ISSF Website you need to provide ISSF
with your name and your address-data, including e-mail-address and payment related data in order
to allow us to perform the contract with you. Such data is used as necessary for the performance of
the contract and stored for the time necessary in such context, e.g. to allow us the assessment of pos-
sible warranty rights, or according to retention periods as legally required, e.g. pursuant to ISSF’s
commercial and tax law obligations. Therefore, such processing is primarily based on Article 6 para.
1 lit.b GDPR.
d)         ISSF News Magazine
ISSF regulary processes the name, the address and the email adress of ISSF News Magazine sub-
scribers. Such data is used as necessary for concluding and performing under the respective contract
with the subscriber, in particular for delivering the ISSF News Magazine and invoices. Therefore,
Article 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR serves as the legal basis for such processing of Personal Data.
Date: July 2019

                                                      -3-                                ISSF Privacy Policy
e)         ISSF Forum and intranet
The use of the ISSF Forum will require further processing of Personal Data by the ISSF. In particu-
lar, the following information will be processed: name, address, e-mail-address, date of birth, IP ad-
dress, all communication made by you on the ISSF Forum.
This information is required to identify the participant’s legitimation, to create and manage your
account, to provide for a safe login and forum environment, to monitor the ISSF Forum’s content to
its compliance with legal provisions and, if necessary, to contact you via your registered contact in-
formation in connection with the management and operation of your account. Therefore, such pro-
cessing is primarily based on Article 6 para. 1 lit.b GDPR.
Upon registration to the ISSF Forum you agree to the processing of your Personal Data for the time
of your participation in the ISSF Forum. Therefore, also Article 6 para. 1 lit.a GDPR may serve as the
legal basis for processing the abovementioned Personal Data in connection with your use of the ISSF
Forum. In case of failure to provide such data, participation in the ISSF Forum will not be granted.
However no other disadvantages will occur when the necessary data is not provided. You may un-
register from the ISSF Forum at any time by informing the ISSF Forum 2024 Operator (for contact
details see the ISSF Forum 2024 - Terms and Conditions). Upon unregistration your Personal Data
will usually be deleted within six months.
With regard to the use of your Personal Data the same applies to the ISSF Website’s intranet. You
may un-register from the intranet at any time by informing privacy@issf-sports.org.
f)         Newsletters and press releases
Upon your subscription the ISSF may use your Personal Data to provide you with information via its
newsletter and press releases. Upon unsubscription your Personal Data will usually be deleted within
six months.
To subscribe for newsletters please register by completing our subscription form on:
www.issf-sports.org/theissf/communication/media/newsletter/subscribe_shootingfriends.ashx.
Articles 6 para. 1 lit.a and b GDPR serve as the legal basis for processing your Personal Data in con-
nection with the newsletter service. To unsubscribe from the newsletter, use the following link:
www.issf-sports.org/theissf/communication/media/newsletter/unsubscribe_shootingfriends.ashx
To subscribe for press releases please register by completing our subscription form on:
www.issf-sports.org/theissf/communication/media/newsletter/subscribe_press.ashx
Articles 6 para. 1 lit.a and b GDPR serve as the legal basis for processing your Personal Data to pro-
vide you with the ISSF press releases. To unsubscribe from the press releases, use the following link:
www.issf-sports.org/theissf/communication/media/newsletter/unsubscribe_press.ashx
For marketing purposes, the ISSF may monitor whether you open and/or click on URLs in our news-
letters in order to notify you about products and events which might be in your interest. Article 6
para. 1 lit.f GDPR serves as the legal basis for processing your Personal Data in this context as such
data processing for direct marketing activities are covered by the legitimate interests of ISSF. Your
Date: July 2019

                                                       -4-                                ISSF Privacy Policy
interests do not outweigh ISSF’s interests as ISSF does not use any data of special category. Such use
of your data complies with your reasonable expectations as the ISSF services are offered free of costs
and our marketing activities do only relate to the world of shooting sport. In addition, you can object
to the use of your data for direct marketing purposes at any time as pointed out below at the section
regarding your rights.
2.         Links to third parties’ websites
The ISSF Website may provide links to third-parties’ websites for the convenience of our users. If
you access those links, you will leave the ISSF Website. ISSF does not control these third-party web-
sites and cannot represent that their policies and practices will be consistent with this Privacy Policy.
For example, other web sites may collect or use personal information about you in a manner differ-
ent from than described in this document. Therefore, you should use other web sites with caution,
and you do so at your own risk. ISSF encourages you to review the privacy policy of any web site be-
fore submitting personal information. It is also likely that your data will be transferred to different
countries, in particular the United States of America, which might not have standard of data protec-
tion as your home country. The third party service is also likely to use cookies. In order to get infor-
mation on the purpose and scope of data collection and procession by the third party websites pro-
vider, please consult the respective privacy policy of that provider.
The ISSF Website displays the following social links: Facebook Inc., 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto,
California         94304,        USA:          http://www.facebook.com/policy.php;            Instagram:
https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388; Google Inc. (including YouTube), 1600 Amphithea-
ter             Parkway,          Mountainview,               California          94043,              USA:
https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners; Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San
Francisco, California 94103, USA: https://twitter.com/privacy; Livestream LLC, 195 Morgan Ave-
nue, Brooklyn, NY, 11237, USA: https://livestream.com/terms/privacy.
3.         Information on the transfer of Personal Data
ISSF does not sell, rent, or lease any individual’s Personal Data to anyone for marketing purposes,
and will take commercially reasonable steps to maintain the security of this information. However,
the ISSF reserves the right to supply any such information to any organisation into which it may
merge or change in the future. ISSF only discloses your Personal Data to third parties, if
- you gave explicit consent pursuant to Article 6 para. 1 lit.a GDPR;
- the disclosure is required pursuant to Article 6 para. 1 lit.f GDPR to assert, exercise or defend legal
claims and there is no reason to believe that you have an overriding interest in not disclosing your
data;
- ISSF is obligated pursuant to Article 6 para. 1 lit.c GDPR to release your personal information pur-
suant to judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants, or other orders or
- it is lawful and pursuant to Article 6 para. 1 lit.b GDPR required for the performance/settlement of
contractual relationships with you.
The ISSF Website’s main database is located in Germany. ISSF Website’s back-up servers are located
in Switzerland where, according to the European Commission, an adequate level of data protection is
ensured. ISSF only transfers your Personal Data to other third states outside the European Union if
(i) you have consented to such transfer after having been informed of the possible risks of such trans-
Date: July 2019

                                                    -5-                                  ISSF Privacy Policy
fer due to the absence of an adequacy decision or other appropriate safeguards, or (ii) the transfer is
necessary for the performance of services in relation with the ISSF Website or the implementation of
pre-contractual measures taken at your request, or (iii) the transfer is necessary for the perdormance
of a contract conclude in your interest between ISSF and another natural or legal person, or (iv) one
of the other conditions stipulated in Article 49 para. 1 GDPR applies.
4.         Information about and access to your Personal Data
In the following the ISSF informs you about your rights of information about and access to your Per-
sonal Data.
a)          Right of access
Pursuant to Article 15 GDPR you have the right to obtain from the ISSF confirmation as to whether
or not Personal Data concerning you is being processed. Where that is the case, you have the right to
access the collected data and the following information: The source and the recipients of the data,
the purpose of its processing and information about your rights as provided here under Number 4.
Upon request a copy of such information shall be provided to you free of charge, any further copies
may be provided in exchange for a reasonable fee based on administrative costs.
b)         Right to rectification
Pursuant to Article 16 GDPR you have the right to obtain from the ISSF without undue delay the
rectification of inaccurate Personal Data concerning you. Taking into account the purposes of the
processing, you have the right to have incomplete Personal Data completed, including by means of
providing a supplementary statement.
c)         Right to erasure
Pursuant to Article 17 GDPR you have the right to obtain from the ISSF the erasure of Personal Data
concerning you without undue delay once the ISSF does not have further legal grounds for pro-
cessing your data.
d)         Right to restriction of processing
Pursuant to Article 18 GDPR you have a right obtain from the ISSF restriction of processing when
there is uncertainty over either the accuracy of the data process, the lawfulness of the data process or
the effectiveness of your withdrawl of consent. You may also obtain restriction when the ISSF no
longer needs the Personal Data, but they are required by you for the establishment, exercise or de-
fence of legal claims. Restriction means that such Personal Data shall, with the exception of storage,
only be processed with the data subject's consent or for the establishment, exercise or defence of
legal claims or for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person or for reasons of
important public interest of the Union or of a Member State.
e)         Right to data portability
Pursuant to Article 20 GDPR where the data has been provided based on your consent or on a con-
tract and the data processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive the
Personal Data, which you have provided, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable
Date: July 2019

                                                       -6-                              ISSF Privacy Policy
format and have the right to transmit those data to another controller without hindrance from the
ISSF.
f)         Right to object
Pursuant to Article 21 GDPR you have the right to object, on grounds relating your particular situa-
tion, at any time to processing of your Personal Data, when
- processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the
    exercise of official authority vested in the ISSF (Article 6 para. 1 lit.e GDPR) or
- processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by ISSF or by a third
    party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and free-
    doms of the data subject which require protection of Personal Data, in particular where the data
    subject is a child (Art. 6 para. 1 lit.f GDPR).
When you object the ISSF may only process your data if compelling legitimate grounds are demon-
strated. Irrespective of this you may object at any time to processing of Personal Data for marketing
purposes.
g)         Right to revoke consent
Where the processing of your data is based on your consent, you have the right to withdraw consent
at any time by informing privacy@issf-sports.org. This, however, does not affect the lawfulness
of processing based on your consent before the withdrawal.
h)         Right to lodge a complaint
Pursuant to Article 77 GDPR you may at any time lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.
5.         Data Security
The ISSF takes data security very seriously. Taking into account the state of the art, the costs of im-
plementation and the nature, scope, context and purposes of processing, as well as the risk of varying
likelihood and severity for your rights and freedoms, the ISSF implents appropriate technical and
organisational measures to ensure a level of security which is appropriate to the represented risk.
6.         Amendments
ISSF reserves the right to update this data privacy policy from time to time. Updates of this privacy
policy will be published on this website. Any changes to this privacy policy apply as of their publica-
tion on our website. ISSF therefore recommends that you visit this website regularly so that you are
appropriately informed about any updates and changes.
If you have any question regarding the processing of your Personal Data by the ISSF on basis of this
Privacy Policy please refer to privacy@issf-sports.org.
Date: July 2019
